AMANDA ZAPATA

(407)-844-3730 | amandazapata802@gmail.com | Orlando, FL | www.linkedin.com/in/zapamanda

Technical Writer

Summary: I am transitioning my career experience in the technical communications field and am using a portfolio to showcase my writing skills. I have three years of experience in teaching English Language Arts and managing projects. My love for both technology and writing has led me to pursue a technical writing career. I am self-taught and am learning more every day!

WORK EXPERIENCE:

9th Grade English Teacher, Osceola County District Schools | Saint Cloud, FL

August 2021 - May 2023

- Increased reading proficiency skills in students from 48% to over 70% in 5 months by deliberately practicing and mastering test-taking strategies.
- Achieved higher writing test scores among students by 74% in 4 months by proofreading essays and facilitating writing workshops.
- Stayed highly organized by pushing out detailed written communication by messaging parents after posting grade reports with over 170 students.
- Assisted navigating educational technology in the classroom such as Office 365 products to promote problem-solving skills by easily editing and revising essays.

Student Teacher, Liberty Middle School | Chickasaw, FL

Jan. 2021 - May 2021

- Improved student data by assisting mentor teacher tutor students 1-on-1 with copywriting and editing tasks.
- Provided simultaneous supervision in a fast-paced environment to increase engagement with over 100+ in-person and online students in a hybrid setting using Zoom and Teams.

English III Student Teacher, Florida Virtual School | Remote

Sep. 2020– Dec. 2020

- Utilized Google Sheets to track student and parent communication and increased communication.
- Increased detailed written and oral feedback by 45% in 3 months through implementation of personalized responses on student assignments.

Summer Intern, Siemens Energy | Orlando, FL

May 2018 - July 2018

- Incorporated writing skills from internal documentation to articles about the internship experience that increased overall engagement by on an internal platform.
- Applied instructional design and journalism to create company flyers, brochures, and postcards advocating for S.T.E.A.M. education in local public schools in 2 months.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Secondary Education in English Language Arts

May 2021

University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

3.9 GPA | UCF Top Ten Knight | Dean's List every semester

SKILLS

Leadership, Copyediting, Office 365, Project Management, Research, Proofreading, Cultural Competence, Technical Writing